Revital Berko

Fair Lawn, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Revital-Berko/6a5e405be3823ac0

Experienced Agile Project Manager offering over 6 years of diverse experience in the software development industry and Agile methodology.

Capable of delivering large-scale software and Web development projects on time and on budget by effectively collaborating, facilitating, leading and coaching multiple Scrum teams.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE CONSULTANT

- 2013 to Present
- · Agile project management consultation and support
- Health and Fitness mobile application design and development (startup team).

AGILE PROJECT MANAGER

AMDOCS - 2012 to 2013

Planned and Managed the successful completion of 8 software development projects in a cross-touchpoint (mobile and web) application, which enabled customers to self-manage their account and shop online. (~300MM).

- Successfully established, coached and mentored 2 new self-organizing scrum teams. Resulted in continuous increasing productivity and deliveries on time with proven quality.
- Defined the projects' scope, managed risks along the way and significantly improved reports quality.
- Coordinated and collaborated daily with product owners and teams in multiple sites.
- Utilized Restful based framework and Integrated Amdocs Portfolio products.

Major Accomplishments:

- Led and managed Core Software Products Upgrade project reducing upgrade time by 60% as well as defects rate by 50%.
- Led the future freeze defects cleanup coordinating between 8 teams in 2 different sites. Joint efforts reduced defects number by 80%.
- Directly managed 6 developers who I mentored and developed which resulted in them receiving promotions.

AMDOCS - 2006 to 2013

2006-2013

Global Corporation that provides customer experience solution portfolios to service providers in the communications, media, and entertainment industries: Including billing, customer management, mobile financial services etc.

CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER

AMDOCS - 2010 to 2012

- Built and led R&D core development team in an agile environment.
- Developed Amdocs Self-service product for Telco companies.
- Led the scrum lifecycle activities: sprint planning, daily stand up, commitment, retrospective.

Major Accomplishments:

- Led a continuous integration task force and improved build time by 70%.
- Increased productivity was improved by 20%.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

AMDOCS - 2007 to 2010

- Designed, developed, and maintained Amdocs Self Service Product as part of the core R&D team.
- Created Java based portlets and product frameworks using WebSphere/WebLogic.

SOFTWARE TESTING ENGINEER (INTERNSHIP)

AMDOCS - 2006 to 2007

Maintained scripts and execution of automated test cases for Amdocs Charging product

IT & COMMUNICATION SYSTEM TRAINING OFFICER

ISRAELI DEFENSE FORCES - 1998 to 2000

Served 2 years as a Platoon Commander of both IT Systems and Communication System Training departments.

- Trained in MAMRAM, the #1 ranked software-engineering training in the Israeli tech industry Major Accomplishments:
- Received Certificate of Excellence.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE in INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

Ben-Gurion University of the Negev August 2007

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Agile methodology Iteration/Sprint planning and reviews
- Team building and mentoring Story based development expertise
- Strong passion for process improvement Deep knowledge in Agile Project Management
- Empowering team members Ability to multi-task
- Strong technical background Multiple projects management
- Excellent Communication skills Cross-functional environment management
- Problem Resolution and Decision Making Independent, fast learner and accountable

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java/J2EE, Spring, RESTful WebService, Portlets, SQL, Javascript, Ajax, DOJO.
- DB: Oracle.
- Web Servers: Weblogic and WebSphere
- · UNIX: Ksh scripting